Syed Khurram Munir

khurrammunir9522@gmail.com +923354182560 Lahore, Punjab

Summary

Highly motivated Software Developer with a passion for combining design and programming. Experienced in collaborating within cross-functional teams to create visually appealing and functional applications. Dedicated to maintaining coding excellence and driving exceptional user experiences.

Experience

Software Developer

Transcure • Lahore, Punjab

03/2023 - Present

- Collaborated with a team to translate design frames into responsive and interactive web and mobile applications
- Developed and maintained user-friendly interfaces with a keen eye for detail, ensuring a seamless user experience
- Utilized best coding practices to facilitate code maintenance and scalability
- Created and maintained comprehensive design, architecture, and process documentation for software applications
- Worked closely with cross-functional teams in an agile environment to ensure successful product delivery
- Contributed actively to solutions design processes, providing valuable insights and creative problemsolving
- · Championed the goal of exceptional customer experiences through user-centric design and implementation.

Software Developer

Einnovention Software Solutions LLC • Lahore, Punjab

11/2021 - 03/2023

- Developed and implemented user-friendly interfaces using React.js and JavaScript, ensuring a seamless user experience.
- Collaborated with designers and backend developers to gather requirements and translate them into technical specifications, ensuring efficient project execution.
- Utilized modern frontend development tools and workflows such as Webpack, Babel, and NPM to streamline the development process and improve productivity.
- Optimized applications for maximum performance, focusing on speed and scalability to enhance the user experience.
- Conducted thorough code reviews, ensuring code quality, adherence to best practices, and identifying areas for improvement.
- Troubleshot and debugged issues that arose during development and testing, providing timely solutions and ensuring smooth project delivery.
- Contributed to the improvement of development processes and tools, identifying areas for enhancement and implementing solutions to increase efficiency.

Identified and resolved browser compatibility issues across different devices and browsers.

Frontend Developer

Code desk Private Limited • Lahore, Punjab

12/2020 - 11/2021

- General web development, including building landing pages, small web applications.
- Manage website development projects from initial design through completion.
- Worked closely with developers and clients to meet project requirements, goals, and desired functionality.
 Created modular, responsive website using modern CSS techniques and JavaScript libraries.
- Developed and maintained user-facing websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Identified and resolved browser compatibility issues across different devices and browsers.
- Performed unit tests to identify bugs or errors prior to release cycles.
- Troubleshot minor problems and reported larger technical issues.

Software Developer Intern

TV2U Private Limited • Lahore, Punjab

03/2020 - 11/2020

- Enjoyed working with TV2U as a software developer. Had worked in REACT JS and VUE JS for frontend development.
- Worked closely under the supervision of the Principal Software Engineer.
- Day to day, I learned new development skills and techniques while collaborating with the development team.
- I also learned full-stack development tools to meet advanced industry requirements.
- Delivered a project for a digital retail store where customers could enjoy an online buying experience by selecting products and adding them to the cart. The admin of the website had the ability to add, modify, and delete products and categories. The website included a login and registration system. The website was user-friendly and responsive. I had built APIs to connect Laravel to Nuxt.js and applied CRUD operations.

Education

MCS

Virtual University of Pakistan 03/2019

BSC

Punjab Group of Colleges • Lahore, Punjab 08/2016

ICS

Punjab Group of Colleges • Lahore, Punjab 09/2014